They were deadly on the ground. Now they have wings.
Con Air is a action, thriller, crime film directed by Simon West.
Newly-paroled former US Army ranger Cameron Poe is headed back to his wife, but must fly home aboard a prison transport flight dubbed
"Jailbird" taking the “worst of the worst” prisoners, a group described as “pure predators”, to a new super-prison.
Poe faces impossible odds when the transport plane is skyjacked mid-flight by the most vicious criminals in the country led by the
mastermind — genius serial killer Cyrus "The Virus" Grissom, and backed by black militant Diamond Dog and psychopath Billy Bedlam.
Cameron Poe, played by Nicolas Cage.
Agent Vince Larkin, played by John Cusack.
Cyrus "The Virus" Grissom, played by John Malkovich.
Nathan "Diamond Dog" Jones, played by Ving Rhames.
"Baby-O" O'Dell, played by Mykelti Williamson.
"Pinball" Parker, played by Dave Chappelle.
Con Air is a 1997 American action thriller film directed by Simon West (in his feature directorial
debut) and starring Nicolas Cage, John Cusack and John Malkovich in the lead roles.
Written by Scott Rosenberg and produced by Jerry Bruckheimer, the film centers on
a prison break aboard a JPATS aircraft, nicknamed as "Con Air".
It features an ensemble supporting cast of Steve Buscemi, Ving Rhames, Colm Meaney,
Mykelti Williamson and Rachel Ticotin, with Monica Potter, Dave Chappelle, M.
Gainey, and Danny Trejo in minor roles.
Con Air was released theatrically on June 6, 1997 by Buena Vista Pictures through Touchstone Pictures and was
a box office success, grossing over $224 million against a production budget of $75 million.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the acting, musical score and action
sequences but criticized the inconsistent tone, direction and character development.
The film achieved a cult following among action
aficionados and the Nicolas Cage fanbase.
It received Oscar nominations for Best Sound and Best Original Song for "How
Do I Live", performed on the soundtrack by Trisha Yearwood.
The film explores themes of undercover, ambush,
war veteran, psychopath, bravery.
The tone is dark and intense.